澄心委员会（一）
让我给你讲讲
Well, let me start by giving just
澄心委员会的贵格会历史。
a Quaker history of the Clearness Committee.
澄心委员会在350年前
The Clearness Committee has emerged within
贵格会创建之初就出现了，
the beginnings of Quakerism 350 years ago,
其缘由很简单，
for a very simple reason,
贵格会是基督教教会的一种形式，
Quakers  were a form of the Christian Church that
没有牧师领导。
had no pastoral leadership.
他们没有受命的神职人员。
They didn't have ordained clergy.
他们没有一个指定的人
They didn't have a designated person
去处理问题和难题，
to go to with problems issues questions,
因此他们需要创造公共结构，
so they needed  to invent communal structures that
使社区能够围绕着这些问题进行对话和处理，
enabled the community to come together around things
而在其它教堂中人们通常把
that in other churches people would take
这些问题带到牧师或神父那里去寻求帮助。
into the pastor's office or into the priests office.
当然，其中要处理的一件事是，
One of those thing of course is
人们生活中挣扎的特定议题。
that people struggle with certain issues in life.
他们可能有职业上的挣扎，
they may have a vocational struggle
或者可能有关系上的挣扎，
or they may have a relationship struggle
或者可能有围绕问题意义上的挣扎。
or they may have a struggle around questions of meaning.
所以澄心委员会的出现
And so the Clearness Committee emerged as a way
是为了让该宗教团体的五六名成员
for five or six members from that religious community
与有问题的人坐在一起，
to sit with a person who had a problem
并且帮助那个人唤起
and to help that person evoke
与自己内在导师的联结。
the resources of his or her inner teacher.
这其实是以贵格会的两个关键信仰为前提。
It's really premise two key Quaker beliefs.
其一，我们每个人都有一个
One is we all have an inner teacher that
比世界上任何人都知道我们需要什么的内在导师。
knows what we need than anybody else in the world.
其二，为了接触到那个
And the other is that in order to get access to
内在导师，我们需要社区的帮助。
that inner teacher we need to be in community.
一个可以帮助我们整理和筛选
A community that can help us sort and sift
我们觉得我们听到的是什么声音的社区。
what voice it is we think we're hearing.
因为贵格会成员像其他人一样
Because Quakers know as well as anybody else
知道我们内在有不同的声音。
that we have a variety of voices within us.
我们有恐惧的声音，
There's a voice of fear,
有小我的声音，等等。
there's a voice of egos, etc.
而且我们还有内在导师的声音。
And there's a voice of the inner teacher.
所以他们知道你
So they understood that you
不能只是独自坐在房间中，
couldn't just sit alone in your room
并且说，“哦，有一个内在导师，
and say, "Oh, there's an inner teacher,
我最好起身并跟随”，
I better get up and follow,
而是告诉我们，所有人都需要社区
but that we all need community
来帮助我们进行分类和筛选内在之声。
to do that sorting and sifting.
但是我们所需的社区
But the kind of community
不是那种会告诉你
that was needed was not a community that
答案是什么的社区，
would tell you what your answer was,
而是这样一个社区，
it was rather a community that in the great
用女权主义神学家
words of a feminist theologian named
内尔·莫顿的话来说，帮助你聆听、
Nell Morton would help hear you into speech,
越来越深地倾听，
deeper and deeper speech,
越来越真实地聆听的社区。
more and more truthful speech.
由此产生的澄心委员会，
And so the  Clearness Committee that resulted from
由五六个人组成，
that consists of five or six people who
他们与你坐在一起几个小时，
sit with you for several hours
在此期间，他们基本上什么都不做，
and during that process of time,
除了问你一些诚实的开放的问题。
basically do nothing but ask you honest open questions.
这里有一些隐含的东西，
There's a lot sort of hidden and what I just said
我刚才说得的话听起来很简单，
even though it sounds quite simple,
因为事实证明，
because it turns out
向你提出诚实而开放的问题是
that asking you honest open questions is
一项非常艰巨的任务。
a very demanding assignment.
我们非常擅长于问一些
We are so gifted at asking questions
既不诚实又不开放的问题，
that aren't honest and open,
而这些问题实际上是些建议或变相的演讲。
but that are really advices or speeches in disguise.
如果我问，“你是否想过要去看治疗师”，
So if I ask have you thought about seeing a therapist,
这就不是一个诚实而开放的问题。
that's not an honest open question.
我想说的其实是，
I'm really trying to say,
我认为“你应该去看治疗师”，
I think you ought to see a therapist
而这是我偷偷提出建议的方式。
and here's my way of sneaking that advice in.
所以这个方法有很多要求
So there's a lot in here that is
很高的部分，需要我们进行练习。
demanding that requires practice.